Guide to the Harry E. Cole papers, 1763-1937
Cole, Harry E. papers, 1763-1937
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harry E. Cole papers, 1763-1937
698
Harry E. Cole.
2.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, diaries, indentures, poems, genealogies, photo album, letterbook, notebook, and scrapbooks.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, diaries (1912-36), indentures, poems, genealogies, photo album, and other materials on the early and contemporary history of Salem, Washington County, New York, including papers relating to the raising of regiments for the Revolutionary War and compensation for the same; a general history of Washington Academy; a Salem letterbook (1794-1882); a notebook of outlines of theological studies kept by Henry M. Davis; two scrapbooks of Albany clippings; and diaries and correspondence of Harry Cole.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
After his retirement from the State Department of New York, Harry E. Cole became historian for Salem, New York.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, diaries (1912-36), indentures, poems, genealogies, photo album, and other materials on the early and contemporary history of Salem, Washington County, New York, including papers relating to the raising of regiments for the Revolutionary War and compensation for the same; a general history of Washington Academy; a Salem letterbook (1794-1882); a notebook of outlines of theological studies kept by Henry M. Davis; two scrapbooks of Albany clippings; and diaries and correspondence of Harry Cole.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cole, Harry E.; Davis, Henry M.; Washington Academy (Salem, N.Y.)
Subjects:
Military service, Voluntary.; Theology--Study and teaching.
Places:
Salem (N.Y.)--History.; United States--Armed Forces--Pay, allowances, etc.; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; Washington County (N.Y.)--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Genealogies.; Indentures.; Photographs.; Poems.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Mss. folder (photocopies), 1763-1769 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder (some photocopies), 1770-1784 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder (some photocopies), 1785-1787 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1787-1799 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder (2 photocopies), 1810-1819 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder (2 photocopies), 1820-1833 (Box 1)
- Printed volume: The Illustrated Self-Instructor in Phrenology and Physiology by O.S. and L.N. Fowler (New York: Fowler and Wells, publishers, 1859), with chart of the character of Emma C. Wilder as given by Nelson Sizer, Feb. 7, 1857 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1846-1859 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder (some photocopies), 1862-1863 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder (some photocopies), 1864-1868 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1870-1879 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1880-1883 (Box 1)
- Folder, 1884-1888 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1890-1898 (Box 1)
- Pamphlet--reprint of memorial to Dr. John Francis Williams from The American Geologist, Mar. 1892 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1900-1909 (Box 1)
- The Salem Review-Press, supplement, Dec. 20, 1901, on 10th anniversary of the Bancroft Public Library (Box 1)
- Invitation to witness electrocution, at Auburn Prison, of Leon F. Czolgosz alias Fred Nieman (man who shot President Wm. McKinley at Buffalo, N.Y.), issued to Chas. F. Rattigan of Auburn (he became Sup't. of Prisons later), Oct. 23, 1901 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1910-1915 (Box 1)
- Photograph: 4 3/16" x 6 3/16" portrait of Harry E. Cole, Albany, Mar. 1911 (Box 1)
- Photograph: 6 15/16" x 13 1/2" N.Y.S. Assembly of 1911 (H.E. Cole and Al Smith indicated) (Box 1)
- Printed "Thanksgiving Proclamation" by Gov. John A. Dix, 1911 (Box 1)
- Mss. folder, 1916-1919 (Box 2)
- Booklet: Soldiers Individual Pay Record Book, issued to Hugh B. Cole, 1918-1919 (Box 2)
- Mss. folder, 1920-1925 (Box 2)
- Business record cards, 1922-1925 (Box 2)
- Business record cards, 1926-1927 (Box 2)
- Invitation to opening of the Holland Tunnel between N.Y. and N.J., Nov. 12, 1927 (Box 2)
- Business record card, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
- Program of inauguration of F.D. Roosevelt as N.Y.S. governor, Jan. 1, 1929 (Box 2)
- Mss. folder, 1930-1932 (Box 2)
- Invitation to opening of the George Washington Bridge, Oct. 24, 1931 (Box 2)
- Photograph: 5" x 7", Lt. Gov. Lehman and family on inspection tour of state institutions, Aug. 10, 1932 (Box 2)
- 27 typescript pp. (bound), Recollections of Salem, N.Y., Sept. 1932 (Box 2)
- Booklet: History of the 309th Machine Gun Battalion 78th Division, American Expeditionary Forces, Côte d'Or, France, 1919 (Box 2)
- 1925 Year Book of Washington Academy, Salem, N.Y. (Box 2)
- Invitation to Inaugural Ball honoring Gov. F.D. Roosevelt, Dec. 31, 1930 (Box 2)
- Pamphlet: The 100th Anniversary of the N.Y.S. Agricultural Society, Jan. 20, 1932 (Box 2)
- Mss. folder, 1933 (Box 3)
- Mss. folder, 1934 (Box 3)
- Mss. folder, 1935 (Box 3)
- Mss. folder, 1936-1937 (Box 3)
- Volumes
  - Steno pad: H.E. Cole address written on front cover. List postmasters and dates for Salem and vicinity, 1825-1932 (Box 3)
  - Notebook: May A. Marston written on front cover. Genealogical notes on Fitch family and related families (Box 3)
  - Anniversary Souvenir (N.Y. press of T.A. Wright, 1896 ), published copy of the proceedings at anniversary celebration of the U.P. Church, Salem, N.Y., 100pp. (Box 3)
  - Paperback: Betts-Roosevelt Letters (3rd edition) by Charles H. Betts, published by the Lyons Republican Co., Lyons, N.Y., 1912, 102 pp., autographed copy (Box 3)
  - Some Facts Concerning Our Local History, by Willoughby Lord Sawyer, Swigert Press, Hudson Falls, N.Y., 1930, 62 pp., autographed copy (Box 3)
  - The History of a Remarkable Law Suit: John W. Kinney vs. N.Y. Central R.R. Co., by Hamilton Ward [attorney for plaintiff], printed by Batavia Times, Batavia, N.Y., n.d., 49 pp. (Box 3)
  - History of the Presbytery of Argyle of the United Presbyterian Church of North America and its Associate and and Associate Reformed Predecessors, 1880 (Box 6)
  - Pamphlet: Scripture History for the Young, by the Rev. John Howard, Virtue & Yorston, Publishers, New York, 1865 ("The Illustrated Edition") (Box 6)
  - Pamphlet: The Centennial Discourse on the One Hundredth Anniversary of the First Baptist Church, Warren, R.I., by A.F. Spalding, Nov. 15, 1864 (Providence: Knowles, Anthony & Co., printers, 1865 ) (Box 6)
  - Pamphlet: Minutes of the Rhode Island Baptist Anniversaries, 1902 (Box 6)
  - Paperback book: An Antidote Against Melancholy, 1884, N.Y., printed by T.L.D.V. for Pratt Manufacturing Co. (apparently for free distribution to patrons), 123 pp. "Compounded of Choice Poems, Jovial Songs, Merry Ballads, and Witty Parodies. Most pleasant and diverting to read." Stamped: Cole Memorial, Bancroft Public Library, Salem, NY (Box 6)
- Miscellaneous
  - Folder marked "Pictures and Broadsides" (Box 4)
  - Mss. volume [not in folder]: Constitution and minute book of the Young People's Literary Guild, Nov. 12, 1877-Feb. 23, 1878; minutes of the Literary Guild of Salem, Oct. 7, 1878-1881. [The two names were apparently used interchangeable. Meetings were held during the fall and winter months only.] (Box 4)
  - Sally Wright Cole, 1797-1859 (Box 4)
  - Folder marked "Poems, postcards, etc." (Box 4)
  - Folder marked "Booklets" (not listed) (Box 4)
  - Genealogy and undated mss. material (Box 5)
- Diaries
  - Mrs. H.E. Cole, 1912 (Box 6)
  - Mrs. H.E. Cole, 1913 (Box 6)
  - [no name, looks like same handwriting], 1915 (Box 6)
  - Mrs. H.E. Cole, 1921 (Box 6)
  - Mrs. H.E. Cole, 1924 (Box 6)
  - [no name, H.E. Cole], 1934 (Box 6)
- Volumes loose on shelf
  - Photograph album
  - Scrapbook, H.E. Cole, [1886-1889]-1911
  - Scrapbook, [1912-1918]-1932
  - Diary of H.E. Cole, 1927
  - Salem receipts, etc., pasted in vol., 1794-1882
  - Theological Common Place Book of Henry M. Davis, loose Davis family items inside, 1834, 1806-1868